Finding aid for the Ohio Health Sciences Library Association Records
Medical Heritage Center
Ohio Health Sciences Library Association Records
1982-2014
Medical Heritage Center
Ohio Health Sciences Library Association
3.5 linear feet
This collection serves as the official records of the Ohio Health Sciences Library Association.
Spec.200104.OHSLA
History of Ohio Health Sciences Library Association
On March 11, 1994 in Columbus, Ohio, members of the State Council for Ohio Health met with the Ohio Health Information Organization (O.H.I.O.) to merge and launch a new and broader based organization, the Ohio Health Sciences Library Association (OHSLA). It was believed that this merger would produce a stronger organization that could better represent the organization in the time of financial downsizing, political upheaval, and ever increasing technology. This merger also provided a wide geographical base of members and offices. Since 1994, OHSLA has had biannual meetings in the spring and fall.
Scope and Content
The Ohio Health Sciences Library Association Records (approximately 3.5 linear feet) contains records of the organization accumulated by OHSLA members.
Statement of Arrangement
Series I: Administration (9 files) contains material related to the administration of OHSLA. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. Series II: Committees and Meetings (57 files) contains material primarily about the executive committee meetings and the fall and spring meetings. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. Series III: History (1 box) contains material about the history of OHSLA. Items of note include files about the Ohio Health Information Organization and the newsletter, OHSLA Voice. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. Series IV: Media (1 box) contains photographs and CDs. This series is arranged by type of media. Series V: Oversized (1 box) contains oversized material. This series is arranged by item.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open to the public and is available for viewing in the Medical Heritage Center. Materials do not circulate and must be used in the supervised reading room. Restrictions, including copyright, may exist and some materials may be too fragile to photocopy or digitize. The MHC charges for duplication services, which must be performed by staff.
Other Finding Aid
https://hsl.osu.edu/sites/default/files/Spec200104OHSLA_2.pdf
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Medical sciences
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series I: Administration (9 files) contains material related to the administration of OHSLA. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically., 1993-2008
  - Budget Performance, 1995-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1993-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Checkbook Transactions, 1995-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Financial Reports, 1995-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Officer Duties, No Date (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Policy and Procedure Manual, 2000-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Budget, 1994-2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scholarship Program, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Treasurers Report, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Committees and Meetings (57 files) contains material primarily about the executive committee meetings and the fall and spring meetings. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically., 1994-2010
  - Archives Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Communications Committee, 1995, 1999, 2001 - 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Editorial Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee, No Date (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Executive Committee, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Executive Committee, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Executive Committee, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Executive Committee, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Executive Committee, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Executive Committee, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Executive Committee, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Executive Committee, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Executive Committee, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Executive Committee, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fall Meeting, No Date (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fall Meeting, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fall Meeting, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Fall Meeting, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fall Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Fall Meeting, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Fall Meeting, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Fall Meeting, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fall Meeting, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Fall Meeting, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Fall Meeting, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fall Meeting, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Fall Meeting, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Fall Meeting, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Fall Meeting, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Hospital Advocacy Committee, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Membership Committee, 1998, 2002, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Nominating and Elections Committee, 2002, 2007, No Date (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - OCLIS, 2001, 2004, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Program Committee, 2007, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Publicity Task Force, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Scholarship Committee, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Spring Meeting, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Spring Meeting, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Spring Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Spring Meeting, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Spring Meeting, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Spring Meeting, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Spring Meeting, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Spring Meeting, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Spring Meeting, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Spring Meeting, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Spring Meeting, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Spring Meeting, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Spring Meeting, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Spring Meeting, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Spring Meeting, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Standing Committees, 1994, 2000, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Webmaster, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Series III: History (1 box) contains material about the history of OHSLA. Items of note include files about the Ohio Health Information Organization and the newsletter, OHSLA Voice. This series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically., 1982-2010
  - About OHSLA, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Booklet - A History of the Ohio Health Sciences Library Association on the Occasion of its Tenth Anniversary, 1994-2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brochure - Medical Librarians Praise the Hospital Bottom Line, No Date (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Charter Members, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Exhibits, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - GMR - State Council for Ohio, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - GMR - State Council for Ohio, 1990 - 2001, 2005 - 2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Logo, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Member Biographical Information, 2002 - 2008, No Date (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Membership Directories, 1994-2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership Directories, 1999-2004, No Date (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter Costs, 2000, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter - OHSLA Voice, 1994-2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter - OHSLA Voice, 2002-2010 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ohio Council of Library and Information Services, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ohio Health Information Organization, No Date (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - OHSLA Announcement List, No Date (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - President Papers, Margaret Moutseous, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Purpose, No Date (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Vision and Mission Statement, No Date (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Website, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Series IV: Media (1 box) contains photographs and CDs. This series is arranged by type of media., 1995-2009
  - Spring Meeting, 18 April 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Fall Meeting, October 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6-10)
  - Medical Librarians Make Connections, April 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Spring Meeting, March 31, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14-23)
  - CD - OHSLA, June 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Photo CD - Spring Meeting, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - Fall Meeting, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Spring Meeting, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 30-35)
  - Fall Meeting, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 36-43)
  - CD - OHSLA Final, No Date (Box 3, Folder 44-45)
  - OHSLA Fall Meeting, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 46-55)
  - Board Members, No Date (Box 3, Folder 56-59)
- Series V: Oversized (1 box) contains oversized material. This series is arranged by item., 2004-2014
  - 3 Part Poster - OHSLA 15th Anniversary Display for the MLA Midwest Chapter Meeting in Columbus, Ohio, October 4, 2009 (Box 4, Piece 1)
  - Blue Table Skirt - Old Logo, No Date (Box 4, Piece 2)
  - Thank You Gift for 10th Anniversary - Commemorative Plaque, Commemorative Pin, and Stand, 2004 (Box 4, Piece 3)
  - Coaster, No Date (Box 4, Piece 4)
  - Pin for 20th Anniversary: OHSLA (2), 2014 (Box 4, Piece 5)